Okay,Rach,that's muffin and espresso,$4.50.
瑞秋，鬆餅加濃縮咖啡4塊5
Ross,double latte,$2.75. Chandler,coffee and a scone,$4.25.
羅斯，雙份拿鐵2塊7毛5 錢德，咖啡和小圓餅4塊2毛5
And Phoebe,herbal tea,$1.25.
菲比，花茶，1塊2毛5
All together that's $12.75.
總共是…12塊7毛5
This coming from the man who couldn't split our $80 phone bill in half.
這是80元電話費除以二 不會除的人
How much do I owe you?
我的鬆餅和拿鐵多少錢？
That's on the house, courtesy of Joey Tribbiani.
你的由喬伊崔比亞尼免費招待
Great. Well,tell him thanks.
真好，幫我謝謝他
And since Joey seems like such a nice guy...
既然喬伊人這麼好
maybe we could go out?
也許我們可以約個會
He's not used to women being so forward...
他不太習慣女人這麼主動
but I could check with him. He says it's okay.
不過我問過他，他說好
Great. Thanks. Bye-bye.
太好了，謝謝，再見
How come our stuff isn't free?
喬伊，為什麼我們不是免費？
It will be when you look like that in a tight skirt.
等你穿窄裙也那麼辣就可以免費了
I'm getting more dates than ever.
真好，我的約會破記錄的多
You're only giving free stuff to the pretty girls?
慢著，你只算美女免費？
Joey,that is so gross!
對啊，好噁心喔
How about a scone on the house,baby?
要不要來一塊免費小圓餅？
I'm pretty.
我是美女
The One With Rachel's Sister
本集播出：「姐妹大比拚」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
-Hey,does anyone have any gum? -I do.
有人有口香糖嗎？ 我有
Here. Sorry.
拿一下
Oh,you know what?
好像是…
No.
不是
Wait a second.
等一下
-I know it's in here. -You know what? I'm good.
我記得我有 算了，不用了
Sorry,I guess it's in my big bag.
抱歉，大概在我的大袋子裡
Say,does anybody have a goldfish?
有人有金魚嗎？
Why are you here? Shouldn't you be at work?
你怎麼回來了？不是在上班？
They sent me home. They said I can't work if I'm sick.
他們叫我回家 說什麼感冒不能做菜
-Sorry you're sick. -I'm not sick!
-真可憐 -我沒有感冒
I don't get sick. Getting sick is for weaklings, it's for pansies.
我才不會感冒 軟弱和娘娘腔的人才會感冒
No one thinks that you're a pansy...
沒有人覺得你娘娘腔
but we do think that you need a tissue.
但我們覺得你需要面紙
I have not been sick in over three years.
我已經3年多沒感冒了
I think you're sick because that used to be in your nose.
我覺得你感冒了，因為…… 那個原本在你的鼻子裡
I'll get tissue.
我幫你拿幾張面紙
I don't need a tissue. I'm fine-d.
我不需要面紙，我很好…哪
When you put a D at the end of fine...
好的後面還加個哪
you're not fine.
就是不好哪
I'm fine-d.
我很好…哪
It's a really hard word to say.
這句話很難說
-Yes? -Hi. Is Rachel here? I'm her sister.
-哪一位？ -瑞秋在嗎？我是她的妹妹
Oh,my God,Jill!
天哪，吉兒
Oh,my God,Rachel!
天哪，瑞秋
Oh,my God,introduce us.
天哪，介紹一下吧
This is Chandler. And you know Monica and Ross.
這位是錢德 你認識摩妮卡和羅斯
And that's Phoebe. And that's Joey.
那是菲比，那是喬伊
-How you doing? -Don't!
-你好嗎？ -別……
Honey,what are you doing here?
你怎麼來了？
Which sister is this?
這是哪個妹妹？
Is this the spoiled one or the one that bit her?
被寵壞的還是憤世嫉俗的？
Daddy cut me off.
老爸斷了我的財源
Never mind,I got it.
我知道了
You know what I said?
你知道我怎麼說？
I said,"I'll hire a lawyer, sue you,take all your money...
我說 「我要請一個律師 把你的錢都告過來」
and cut you off!"
「然後斷了你的財源」
Wow. What did he say?
那他怎麼說？
That he wouldn't pay for my lawyer.
他說不幫我付律師費
Then he told me to learn the value of money...
還叫我跟他唯一自豪的女兒
from the one daughter he's actually proud of.
來學學金錢的價值
Did you hear that? My dad's proud of me.
你們聽到了嗎？我爸以我為榮
My dad's proud of me.
我爸以我為榮
-Rach? -Oh,yeah. Sorry.
-瑞秋？ -好，抱歉
Honey,so what did you do that made Dad cut you off?
爸為什麼不給你錢？
Okay,I bought a boat.
我買了一艘船
You bought a boat?
你買了一艘船？
It wasn't for me, it was for a friend.
不是我要的，是要送朋友的
Boy,did we make friends with the wrong sister.
我們不該跟姐姐交朋友的
I knew it was stupid and I shouldn't have done it...
我知道這樣很蠢很不應該
but she bought me all these CDs and said I had a cute haircut.
但她送我一大堆CD 還說我的髮型很漂亮
And your daddy didn't understand?
而你爸卻不能理解？
I know,and usually I just cry and say I'm sorry and he forgives me.
就是啊 通常我哭著道歉就沒事了
Oh,yes,good criers,the Green girls.
沒錯，格林家的女生最會哭了
I mean,the Green sisters.
我是說格林家的姐妹
Man,no matter how you say it...
不管怎麼說...
it still sounds like you're talking about green people.
聽起來都像蛤蜊
I'm at rock bottom.
我真是冷到極點
This is the best thing that could've happened to you.
吉兒，這是一次最好的教訓
You've needed to get out on your own.
反正你也得獨立
When I did it, at first I was scared, but then look at me now.
我剛獨立時也很害怕 結果現在呢
I am the only daughter that Dad is proud of.
我是唯一讓老爸驕傲的女兒
I can't believe him. How does he expect me to buy stuff?
他真是太扯了 我要怎麼買東西？
Maybe,you know, you won't buy stuff for a while.
那你就先不要買東西
I don't understand.
我不懂
This is what you'll do. You're gonna get a job.
你現在要做的是找一份工作
You're gonna get an apartment.
找一間公寓
And then you will live off the money that you earn.
然後靠你自己賺的錢過活
Okay,I know this is what you did...
好，我知道你是這樣
but that doesn't sound like me.
但這不像我的作風
Okay,but it can be. It can be you.
但你可以做得到 我會幫你
And you can stay with us. Right,Phoebe?
你可以跟我們住 菲比，可以吧？
-Of course, yeah. -Oh,that's so great!
-當然可以 -太好了
Okay,I'm really gonna do this. I don't know how to thank you.
好，那我就來獨立 真不知道該怎麼謝謝你們
Oh,I like cars.
我喜歡汽車
-You all finished? -Yes.
-你吃完了嗎？ -吃完了
Great.
太好了
Okay,here are the tips for this morning.
早上的小費出來了
Jen gets 50, 50 for me and Joey owes 8 dollars.
珍50，我50 喬伊欠8塊錢
-What? -For all the free food you gave away.
-什麼？ -因為你到處送吃的
If it's free, how come you're charging me for it?
既然是送的，為什麼跟我要錢
We don't give anything away unless it's a birthday.
我們只免費招待壽星
What if they came in third in a modeling contest?
那模特兒比賽第三名呢？
No.
不行
Sorry.
抱歉
I just had the hardest day. Some of these are so heavy.
我今天好慘，這些袋子好重
How did you pay? I thought your dad took your credit card.
吉兒，你怎麼有錢？ 你爸不是把信用卡都收走了？
I memorized those numbers when I was 15.
拜託，我15歲就會背卡號了
But look at all the cool make-it-on-my-own stuff I got!
你們看我買的這些獨立行頭
This is my "Please hire me" sweater.
這是「請僱傭我」毛衣N
And these are my "Don't you want to rent me this apartment?" pants.
這是 「你不想把房子租我嗎」褲子
Charging clothes to your dad doesn't qualify as making it on your own.
讓你爸付你的置裝費不算獨立
Oh, Mr. Scientist has to get all technical.
大科學家就是這麼死板
Rachel's not gonna think it's a good idea.
瑞秋真的不會贊成
-So who made her queen of the world? -I would love that job!
-誰封她當女王了？ -我超想當女王的
What's going on?
怎麼樣啊？
Jill!
吉兒
Did you shop?
你跑去逛街嗎？
No.
沒有
They did.
是他們
Yeah,we went shopping!
對，我們跑去逛街
You went shopping?
你們跑去逛街？
Then you came here and paraded it under Jill's nose...
然後把東西秀給吉兒看？
when you know she's trying to quit. That's terrible.
你們明知她想戒掉 你們真差勁
Sorry,Jill.
抱歉 吉兒
So,what'd you get?
你們買了什麼？
Oh,well,all right. Thank you.
我買了…謝謝N
I got this, you know, "I want a job" sweater.
我買了這件 「我要工作」毛衣
And then I got.. These are apartment pants.
還買了這條公寓褲
Apartment pants?
公寓褲？
You've never heard of them?
對，你沒聽過嗎？
Of course I've heard of them.
當然聽過
Ross,what'd you get?
羅斯那你呢？
I got this...
我買了這個…
This.
這個
-A pashmina? -Yeah!
帕什米納（披肩）？ 對
I love these babies.
我愛死它了
Really?
是嗎？
What's a pashmina?
帕什米納是什麼？
It's a rug.
一種小毯子
Jill?
吉兒？
I'm sorry,Rachel.
瑞秋，對不起…
You think that's gonna work on me? I invented that.
拜託，你真以為我會上當？ 淚眼攻勢是我發明的
Right! But I am sorry.
也對，但我真的很抱歉
It's okay. One little setback is okay.
算了，走一次回頭路還好
-But don't let it happen again,okay? -Okay.
-就是別再犯了，好嗎？ -好。
Now,since Daddy paid for all this stuff, I should take it all away.
既然這是老爸付的錢 我應該全都沒收
But I'm just gonna take the pashmina.
不過我沒收披肩就好
And the pants.
還有那條褲子
I'll take it all, because that way, you'll learn the lesson.
還是都沒收好了 這樣你才能得到教訓
All right.
I'm gonna run a couple of errands and I will see you at dinner.
我有事要忙，我們晚餐見
She took all my stuff.
都被她拿走了
Yeah. Everything but the little blue one.
沒錯，除了這個藍色小袋子
That's the best one!
這一樣最棒了
Oh,my God. Thank you so much!
天哪，謝謝你
Well,hey.
Oh,my gosh,that was so lame. Like a pashmina could be a rug.
天哪，你好遜喔 帕什米納怎麼會是小毯子
Oh,yeah? How about you with the "I'm sorry"?
那你呢？「對不起…」
Shut up! I wasn't like that at all.
閉嘴，我哪有那麼噁心
What about what I said about the apartment pants? How dumb was l?
我那個公寓褲呢？夠蠢吧？
-Were you this cute in high school? -Oh,stop.
-你高中時有這麼可愛嗎？ -別鬧了
-No,you stop. -No,you stop.
-你才別鬧了 -你才別鬧了
Why don't I sit here and then you'll both stop it?
你別鬧了 好，我坐中問，你們都別鬧了
Okay. So,what do you want to do?
你想做什麼？
Let's do something crazy.
我們來瘋一下
I know, let's rest and drink lots of fluids.
我知道，我們來多休息多喝水
Okay,I'll rest.
好，我休息
But if I'm going to bed, then you're coming with me.
不過如果我要上床 你也得跟我來
See,that would be impossible to resist if you weren't all...
我本來很難說不 但是你...
drippy here.
鼻水流不停
Are you saying that you don't want to get with this?
你是說你不想要我嗎？
I don't think you should say that even when you're healthy.
你最好連健康時都不要這樣
Come on.
來嘛
Don't take this personally.
我不是針對你
I just can't have sex with a sick person.
我就是沒辦法跟病人上床
I'm with you. I can't have sex with a sick person either. Disgusting!
我也是，我也不跟病人上床 那樣好噁心
But I'm not sick!
但是我沒病
Let me prove it to you.
讓我證明給你看
We are two healthy people in the prime of lime.
我們身強體壯，青春正盛
See, that's the thing, I would like to stay in the "prime of lime."
我就是想繼續身強體壯
Oh,okay,now I'll do it.
好，我有「性」致了
Hey. What's up?
怎麼樣啊？
I think there's something you should know.
有件事或許你應該知道
Better not be about the apartment pants.
最好不是公寓褲的事
I just pitched the idea to my boss at Ralph Lauren and she loved it.
因為我的上司愛死這個構想了
No. It's just,I was...
不是，我...
I was with Ross and Jill after you left...
我剛和羅斯，吉兒在一起
and I'm pretty sure I saw a little spark between them.
我很確定他們之間有火花
-What? -I mean,it's probably nothing.
什麼？ 或許沒事
But I wanted to warn you that there might be something.
我只是想提醒你 他們或許有什麼
-With Ross and Jill? -Yeah.
-羅斯跟吉兒？ -對
With Ross and my sister?
羅斯和我妹妹？
With my sister Jill and my ex-boyfriend Ross?
我妹妹吉兒和我的前男友羅斯？
-Oh,there is no way. -Okay,then.
-不可能的 -那好吧
Oh,my God! I cannot believe that!
我的天哪，我真不敢相信
I don't like it when he dates anyone, but my sister?
不是我反對羅斯交女朋友 但跟我妹？
Isn't that incest or something?
不是等於亂倫嗎？
And they're gonna have sex.
天哪，而且他們會上床
Oh,no! What if he marries her too?
要是他還娶她呢？
This is just terrible. This is just terrible.
太恐怖了，真是太恐怖了
And I can't stop it. I don't own Ross.
而我又不能阻止 羅斯又不是我的
And Jill should be able to do what she wants to do.
而且吉兒有她的行動自由
Oh, my God, I can't believe Ross is marrying my little sister.
我的天哪，羅斯居然要娶我妹妹
This is the worst thing that could've ever happened to me.
這真是我這一生最悲慘的遭遇
But great news about the apartment pants,huh?
不過公寓褲的事真是太好了
That'll be $3.85.
總共3塊8毛5
What? Yesterday you said I was too pretty to pay.
什麼意思？ 昨天你還說我太美不該付錢
It's just, I can't, because my manager said that I..
我不能請客，因為經理說我…
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂…
-Happy birthday,dear Annie.. -Amy!
祝安妮生日快樂 艾美
Amy
艾美
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂
That's weird, today's my birthday too.
真巧，今天也是我的生日
Not in here,it isn't.
在這裡不是
Sorry I'm late. What's up?
抱歉遲到了，什麼事？
I just wanted to see if there were any leads on the old job front.
我只是想問你工作找得怎樣
No. But I walked past three sales and didn't go in.
沒進展 但我經過三家折扣店都沒進去
How strong am I?
我很堅強吧？
That is great.
太好了
You know who doesn't have to job-hunt? Ross.
你知道誰不必找工作？ 羅斯.
-He works at the university. -Yeah?
他在大學教書 是啊
So you guys talked? So you get along? So you're gonna go out?
所以你知道，你們聊過 你們很投緣，你們要約會嗎？
Me go out with Ross? No.
我跟羅斯約會？
God,no. What would make you think that?
當然不會，你哪來的念頭？
Phoebe...
這個…菲比....
said she thought she saw something between you guys.
覺得你們有什麼
I mean,he's nice.
沒有，他人是很好
He's the kind you're friends with, but not the kind you date.
你會想和他做朋友 但不會想和他交往
He's the kind you date, because you did. But me?
你會，你跟他交往過
Not so much.
我就沒什麼興趣
Oh,not so much. What do you mean? Is there something wrong with Ross?
沒什麼興趣？什麼意思？ 羅斯有哪裡不好嗎？
No,no,no. He's just...
沒有，只不過他...
I don't know. You know,he's just a little bookish.
他有點書獃
Are you saying he's a geek?
你覺得他是怪胎？
You think so too?
你也有同感？
No. Ross is not a geek.
不，羅斯不是怪胎
Then let's just say he's not my type.
好，就當他不是我喜歡的類型
Handsome is not your type?
你不喜歡帥哥？
Smart,kind,good kisser.
聰明？好心？吻技一流？
What,those things aren't on your list?
這些不是你的條件？
Ross is great. You'd be lucky to be with him.
羅斯人很好 能跟他在一起是你的福氣
If it means that much, then I'll ask him out.
好，既然你這麼在意 我就約他
Oh,no. That's not what I meant.
不不不，我不是那個意思
You know what? You're right.
你知道嗎？你說得對
He has been really nice to me.
他對我確實很好
Yeah, but he's not your type.
但他不是你的類型
But maybe that's good.
或許這是好事
I'm doing all these different things.
我正在做各種嘗試
Maybe I should just try dating a geek too.
或許也應該跟怪胎約會看看
Yeah,but you don't want to try too much too fast.
但你也別一下子做太多嘗試
You remember what happened to the little girl who...
你記得那個
tried too much too fast,don't you?
一下子做太多嘗試的小女孩吧
What?
什麼？
She died,Jill.
她死了
Chandler!
錢德
What is it,honey? You need some tea? Some soup?
什麼事，你想喝茶？ 還是喝湯？
Calling Dr. Big.
呼叫大雕醫生
Dr. Big to the bed.
大雕醫生請上床
Jeez,honey, I thought you were asleep.
天哪，我以為你睡了
How could I be asleep knowing that you were in the next room?
你就在外面，我怎麼睡得著？
I was asleep.
我倒是睡著了
No,honey. You know what's sexy? Layers.
不，你知道怎樣才性感？ 多穿幾層
Layers are sexy.
多穿幾層才性感
And blankets are sexy. And hot-water bottles are sexy.
被子才性感 熱水瓶更性感
Get into bed. I want to prove I'm not sick.
上床啦，我想證明我沒生病
I want to make you feel as good as I feel.
我想讓你跟我一樣舒服
Would you please get some rest?
我拜託你休息
I'm fine.
我沒事哪
-You're coughing. -No,I'm not.
-你在咳嗽  -我沒有
No,I'm not,I'm laughing.
我沒有，我是在笑
-At what? -Just something I heard before.
-笑什麼？ -我之前聽說的一件事
-Tell me. -No,I don't want it to spoil the mood.
-告訴我 -不，我不想破壞情調
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂
-You're paying for that. -No,it's her birthday.
你出錢 不，今天是她的生日
You've sung "Happy Birthday" to 20 women today.
你已經對二十個女人唱生日快樂
You are no longer authorized to distribute birthday muffins.
-但是… -你失去送生日鬆餅的權限了
Damn it!
媽的
瑞秋
Did you tell your sister to ask me out?
你叫你妹約我嗎？
-Well,yeah. -Oh,wow! I mean,wow.
-對… -哇，真是……哇
I think she's cute,but...
我覺得她很可愛 但...
I never would've thought of going out with her. Never!
我從來沒想過要跟她約會
Really?
真的？
But after you said it's okay, I figured,"Why not?"
不過既然然你說行 我心想：有何不可？
Oh,so not really "never."
所以也不算從來沒想過
I have to say you are a much bigger person than I am.
你真的比我大方多了
I mean,after all we've been through.
我們有那麼多過去
I wish I had a brother to reciprocate.
我… 真希望我有兄弟可以做交換
If you ever date Monica, you have my blessing.
如果你想跟摩妮卡交往 我絕對祝福
And mine.
我也是
Chandler?
錢德
I think I'm sick.
我覺得我病了
Really?
是嗎？
Struck down in the "pribe of libe."
青春不盛了？
Okay,fine,I admit it. I feel terrible.
好啦，我承認，我很不舒服
Will you please rub this on my chest?
幫我在胸口抹藥膏
No,no,no. You are not getting me this way.
不行，你別想騙我上鉤
Come on,I really need your help here.
-我真的需要你幫我… -不行
-Fine,I'll rub it on myself. -Okay.
-好，那我就自己抹 -好
So you're just kind of rubbing it on yourself?
你在往身上抹藥膏？
-Yeah. -It's nice.
-怎樣？ -蠻好的
You kidding me? Is this turning you on?
不會吧？這樣你會興奮？
Yes.
-對
Is it the rubbing or the smell?
-真是太扯了 -是抹的動作還是味道？
It's all very,very good.
都很棒
So you want to go...
想不想…
mix it up?
嘿咻一下？
-Not now,I'm sick. -Oh,come on,you big faker!
-現在不行，我病了 -少來了，大騙子
What about never sleeping with sick people?
你不是不跟病人上床？
Well,that was before all the vaporizing action.
那是在那令人酥麻的動作之前
Okay,if you really want to have sex.
-好吧，如果你真的想做… -好
Worked like a charm.
真夠靈的
Why are you here?
你來這裡幹什麼？
This is where Ross and I are meeting for our date. So,what do you think?
我跟羅斯約在這裡 我的打扮如何？
I don't like it.
我不喜歡
-Really? -It's kind of slutty.
-是嗎？ -有點放蕩
It's yours.
這是你的衣服
Yeah,well,I'm a slut.
我是個賤人
Me too.
我也是
Hi,Jill.
吉兒
Hi...
Rachel.
瑞秋
You're not at home, you're right here.
你不在家，你在這裡
Yeah,I know.
我知道
And I bet you thought it would be weird. But it's not.
你一定以為會很怪，其實不會
Okay.
好
So,well,I'll...
我...
I'll have her home by midnight.
我午夜之前會送她回家
Why aren't you home yet?
你為什麼還沒回家
Is someone there?
外面有人嗎？
Oh,yeah,it's me. Sorry.
有，是我，抱歉
What are you doing here?
你來幹什麼？
I'm just looking out your window...
我只是在看窗外…
at the view.
的風景
What are you guys doing?
你們在幹什麼？
We got some vapor rub in some places.
我們身上沾到藥膏
He brought her back to his apartment.
他把她帶回家了
Who?
誰？
Is that your sister?
那是你妹妹嗎？
She is a slut!
她真是個賤人
Ross is on a date with your sister. How weird is that?
羅斯在跟你妹約會，多奇怪啊
Oh,my God, he's taking off her clothes!
天哪，看，他在脫她的衣服
He's taking off her coat.
他在幫她脫外套
Oh,this is just terrible.
真是太糟糕了
Oh,no,it's not. It's a first date. I'm sure that nothing is gonna...
不會啦，才第一次約會 一定不會有…
He's gonna get some.
他有福了…
Of the glare...
能看到...
from the streetlight out of his apartment.
屋外街燈的燈光
You know, so he's closed the drapes there...
所以他把窗簾拉上
so he can have a nice,pleasant...
好跟你妹妹...
conversation with your little sister.
好好聊一聊
Well,I'm off to bed.
我去睡了
（未完待續）
I don't feel good.
我不舒服
You better not get me sick.
別把感冒傳染給我
I need some fruit or some juice or some....
我需要水果或果汁或…
Or some nothing.
或空氣
There's nothing in here. Who took our food?
冰箱是空的 誰拿了我們的食物？
Can I interest you in a slice of lasagna or a drumstick?
要不要來點千層面或雞腿？
-No,thanks. -Are you sure? It's on the house.
不用了 你確定？免費的喔
-No,thanks. -How about going out with me Friday night?
-不用了 -星期五晚上要不要跟我約會？
-No,thanks. -What are you gonna do.
-不了 -那就沒辦法了